Guide to the Edward Davison Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Edward Davison Papers
1914-1968
YCAL MSS 787
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
8.48
(22 boxes)
Davison, Edward Lewis, 1898-1970
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Peter Davison, 1985.
Arrangement
Organized into nine series: I. Correspondence, 1920-1967. II. Military files, 1942-1950. III. Writings, 1914-1953. IV. Administrative Files, 1940-1949. V. Photographs, 1918-1962. VI. Personal Papers, 1920-1951. VII. Artwork, 1940-1959. VIII. Printed Material, 1919-1959. IX. Subject Files, 1919-1960.
Scope and Contents
The Edward Davison Papers consist of correspondence, subject files, writings, photographs, personal papers, and printed material that document the military and literary careers of Edward Davison. Significant quantities of material relate to Davison's work with the Army Prisoners of War Special Projects Division. Davison oversaw the re-education of German prisoners of war who were brought to the United States during the Second World War. Other material relates to Davison's literary and academic work, particularly to the Writers' Conference and to the faculty of the University of Colorado, where Davison taught.
Edward Davison (1898-1970)
Edward Davison (1898-1970), Scottish-born American poet, professor at the University of Colorado, and director of the United States Army Prisoner of War Special Projects Division.
American poetry -- 20th Century; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Prisoners of War -- Germany; Prisoners of War -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- Prisoners and prisons, American; Photographs; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Peter Davison; Davison, Edward Lewis, 1898-1970; United States. Office of the Provost Marshal General; University of Colorado (Boulder campus) -- Faculty
- Correspondence, 1915-1968; Series I; 2.51; (7 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: Incoming, Outgoing, and Third Party.
  Scope and Contents
  Correspondence is chiefly professional in nature, relating to Davison's military career and to his literary activity.
  - Incoming
    Arranged alphabetically
    - "A" General, 1931-1962, undated (Box 1)
    - Ackerley, Joseph R., 1922 (Box 1)
    - Aldington, Richard, 1942-1948 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Hervey, 1927-1949, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Ann, undated (Box 1)
    - "B" General, 1920-1968, undated (Box 1)
    - Bowes & Bowes, 1922-1926 (Box 1)
    - Bullet, Gerald, 1925-1932 (Box 1)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1941-1956, undated (Box 1)
    - "C" General, 1935-1960, undated (Box 1)
    - Campbell, A. Y., 1923-1927 (Box 1)
    - Canby, Henry Seidel, 1922-1933 (Box 1)
    - "D" General, 1921-1960, undated (Box 1)
    - Dartmouth College Library, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - De la Mare, Walter, 1921-1950, undated (Box 1)
    - Doyle, Joseph, 1950-1951, undated (Box 1)
    - "E" General, 1930-1954, undated (Box 1)
    - "F" General, 1924-1960, undated (Box 1)
    - Ferril, Thomas Hornsby, 1935-1945, undated (Box 1)
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1928-1938, undated (Box 1)
    - Freeman, Jonathan, 1920-1932 (Box 1)
    - Frost, Robert (chiefly copies), 1927-1937 (Box 1)
    - "G" General, 1935-1956, undated (Box 1)
    - G. Bell & Sons, Ltd., 1925-1929 (Box 2)
    - Graves, Robert, undated (Box 2)
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 1931-1940, undated (Box 2)
    - "H" General, 1925-1961 (Box 2)
    - Harper and Brothers, 1926-1952 (Box 2)
    - Hartley, Grizel Buchanan, 1933-1934, undated (Box 2)
    - Hodgson, Ralph and Aurelia, 1940-1958, undated (Box 2)
    - Holme, Peter H. and Jamie S., 1939-1942, undated (Box 2)
    - Horgan, Paul, 1931-1963 (Box 2)
    - Huxley, Aldous and Maria, 1938-1943, undated (Box 2)
    - "I" General, 1961 (Box 2)
    - Isaacs, Stanley, 1935-1947 (Box 2)
    - "J" General, 1949-1955 (Box 2)
    - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1939-1967, undated (Box 2)
    - "K" General, 1928-1967, undated (Box 2)
    - Kendon, Frank, 1921-1956, undated (Box 2)
    - Knight, Eric, 1934-1941, undated (Box 2)
    - "L" General, 1925-1966, undated (Box 2)
    - Lanham, Charles Trueman, 1948-1960 (Box 3)
    - Lennard, R. G., 1926-1952 (Box 3)
    - Lindsay, Nicolas Vachel, 1921-1931 (Box 3)
    - Longmans, Green & Co., 1928-1930 (Box 3)
    - "M" General, 1921-1967, undated (Box 3)
    - McFee, William, 1920-1940 (Box 3)
    - Mann, Thomas, 1940-1941 (Box 3)
    - Marsh, Edwin, 1926, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Marshall, S. L. A., 1947-1952, undated (Box 3)
    - Mencken, H. L., 1927-1940, undated (Box 3)
    - Mizner, Arthur, 1966-1969 (Box 3)
    - Moore, Doris Langley, 1925-1962 (Box 3)
    - Moseley, Edwin, 1950-1951 (Box 3)
    - Munson, Gorham, 1930-1942 (Box 3)
    - "N" General, 1931-1955, undated (Box 3)
    - National Book Awards, 1956-1957; 2 (Box 3)
    - Norlin, George, 1934-1940, undated (Box 3)
    - "O" General, 1937-1956 (Box 3)
    - Orage, A. R., 1930-1934 (Box 3)
    - Osborn, F. J., 1932-1948 (Box 3)
    - "P" General, 1920-1950 (Box 3)
    - "R" General, 1921-1946 (Box 4)
    - Ratcliffe, S. K., 1939-1952, undated (Box 4)
    - Reynolds, George Fuller, 1940-1947, undated (Box 4)
    - Rickward, Edgell, 1919, undated (Box 4)
    - Richards, Ivan A., 1926-1959, undated (Box 4)
    - Richards, Robert, 1941-1948, undated (Box 4)
    - Robinson, Edwin A., 1926-1932 (Box 4)
    - Robinson, Michael Boardman, 1931-1949 (Box 4)
    - Rogers, James Grafton, 1934-1940 (Box 4)
    - "S" General, 1920-1963, undated (Box 4)
    - Sandburg, Carl, 1937-1950, undated (Box 4)
    - Saroyan, William, 1934 (Box 4)
    - Speyer, Leonora, undated (Box 4)
    - Spiral Press, undated (Box 4)
    - Squire, J. C., 1915-50, undated; 4 (Box 4)
    - Stafford, Jean, 1939-1943, undated (Box 4)
    - Strunsky, Simeon, 1927-1941, undated (Box 4)
    - Sweetser, Wesley, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - "T" General, 1920-1967, undated (Box 4)
    - "U" General, 1940-1950 (Box 4)
    - University of Colorado, 1933-1946 (Box 5)
    - University of Miami, 1935-1946 (Box 5)
    - "V" General, 1927-1943 (Box 5)
    - Vanderbilt University, 1935 (Box 5)
    - Vassar College, 1926-1949, undated (Box 5)
    - Victor Gollancz, Ltd., 1932-1947 (Box 5)
    - "W" General, 1923-1959, undated (Box 5)
    - Walcutt, Charles Child, 1950-1951, undated (Box 5)
    - Walcutt, Sue, 1949-1950 (Box 5)
    - Warren, Robert Penn, 1937-1958, undated (Box 5)
    - Washington and Jefferson College, 1947-1949 (Box 5)
    - "Y" General, 1927-1927 (Box 5)
    - Unidentified, 1946-1948, undated; 2 (Box 5)
  - Outgoing
    - "A" General, 1934-1962, undated (Box 6)
    - "B" General, 1938-1961 (Box 6)
    - "C" General, 1927-1950 (Box 6)
    - "D" General, 1938-1946 (Box 6)
    - "F" General, 1927-1935 (Box 6)
    - "G" General, 1929-1945 (Box 6)
    - "H" General, 1940-1964 (Box 6)
    - Harper and Brothers, 1926-1952 (Box 6)
    - "I" General, 1942, 1948 (Box 6)
    - "J" General, 1946-1962 (Box 6)
    - "K" General, undated (Box 6)
    - "L" General, 1928-1967 (Box 6)
    - Longmans, Green & Co., 1929-1930 (Box 6)
    - "M" General, 1935-1969 (Box 6)
    - "N" General, 1935-1956 (Box 6)
    - "O" General, 1937-1946 (Box 6)
    - "P" General, 1941 (Box 6)
    - "R" General, 1926-1948 (Box 6)
    - "S" General, 1932-1949 (Box 6)
    - "T" General, 1935-1967 (Box 6)
    - University of Colorado, 1933-1946 (Box 6)
    - University of Miami, 1938-1946 (Box 6)
    - Vanderbilt University, 1935 (Box 6)
    - Vassar College, 1927-1946 (Box 6)
    - "W" General, 1936-1949 (Box 6)
    - "Y" General, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified, 1940-1950 (Box 6)
  - Third Party
    - Natalie Davison Correspondence
      - "A" - "D" General, 1936-1946 (Box 7)
      - "F" - "G" General, 1934-1938, undated (Box 7)
      - "H" - "N" General, 1935-1959, undated (Box 7)
      - "M" - "R" General, 1935-1948, undated (Box 7)
      - "S" General, 1938-1947, undated (Box 7)
      - "T" - "Z" General, 1943-1949, undated (Box 7)
    - Others, 1922-1956 (Box 7)
- Military Files, 1942-1950; Series II; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Military Files relate chiefly to Edward Davison's role as Director of the Prisoners of War Special Projects Division and include reports, subject files, and correspondence that document the re-education of German citizens in the United States following the Second World War. The series also includes documentation of personnel matters relating to Davison's military career.
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  - Army orientation materials, 1943-1944 (Box 8)
  - Addresses to German prisoners of war, 1946 (Box 8)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: Basic Report, 1944-1945 (Box 8)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects: The re-education of German prisoners of war, statement by General M. Bryan, [1945] June 15 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Notice of classification [3 cards], 1942-1943 (Box 8)
  - Report on the Experimental Administrative School for Selected German Prisoners of War established at Fort Kearney, Rhode Island, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Fact sheets, no. 1-22, circa 1945 (Box 8)
  - Report of the Prisoner of War Special Projects Division, 1945 November 1 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1945 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence relating to Howard Mumford Jones, 1944-1945, undated (Box 8)
  - Journal of Edward Davison, 1944-1946 (Box 9)
  - Report of the Prisoner of War Special Division, 1945 November 1- 1946 February 28 (Box 9)
  - M.S.D. report on prisoners of war, 1943-1944 (Box 9)
  - Newspaper press releases regarding the re-education of German Prisoners of War, 1945, 1948, undated (Box 9)
  - "Re-education of enemy prisoners of war," typescript carbon, undated (Box 9)
  - Camp problems branch: informal preliminary estimate of situation and problems, 1944 July 2 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence relating to Major M. S. McKnight, 1944-1945 (Box 9)
  - Notebooks, 1943-1945 (Box 10)
  - Poetry and artwork of German prisoners of war, undated (Box 10)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: Davison overseas assignment- aborted, 1945 October 4-16 (Box 10)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: historical monograph, undated (Box 10)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: re-education of German prisoners of war, 1944-1947, undated; 3 (Box 10)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: the re-education of German prisoners of war, surveys, undated (Box 10)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: re-education of German prisoners of war, 1945-1946 (Box 10)
  - War Department: Bureau of Public Relations; Press Branch: press releases, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Radio programs about the re-education of German prisoners of war, 1945 (Box 10)
  - A re-orientation program seen through the eyes of German prisoners of war: report, undated (Box 10)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: 201 file, 1943- 1946 (Box 10)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: 201 file, 1943-1945 (Box 10)
  - Prisoner of War Special Projects Division: re-education of German prisoners, 1944-1947, undated (Box 10)
  - Office of the Provost Marshal General Prisoner of War Special Projects Division, organizational chart, undated
- Writings, 1914-1953; Series III; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Organized into three subseries: Writings of Edward Davison, Writings of George Norlin, and Writings of Others.
  The Writings series contains drafts of poems, music, and prose by Davison and by others, including a significant quantity of material by George Norlin, president of the University of Colorado from 1917 to 1942.
  - Writings of Edward Davison
    Arranged alphabetically by title or genre
    - "The Enchanted Heart," lyrics by Edward Davison and Music by Frank Haworth, draft, holograph (copies), undated (Box 11)
    - "Gossip in a Library," typescript, corrected, with clippings, undated (Box 11)
    - "A Halloween admonition and dedication on the occasion of the re-opening on the western campus of the Little Theatre of the University of Colorado," drafts, typescript carbon, annotated, undated (Box 11)
    - "The Heart's Unreason," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1933 (Box 11)
    - "Line of Caponsacchi" (lecture), draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 11)
    - Nine Poems: list of persons to whom book was sent for criticism, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 11)
    - The Ninth Witch: list of persons to whom the book was sent for criticism, typescript, undated (Box 11)
    - Notes, autograph manuscript, undated; 2 (Box 11)
    - Notes regarding Edward Davison's friendship with Robert Frost, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 11)
    - Notes regarding Edward Davison's friendship with Carl Sandburg, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 11)
    - Poems, autograph manuscript, typescript, and typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 11)
    - Poems, holograph, typescript, and typescript carbon, undated (Box 11)
    - "Poetry Undefined," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 11)
    - Prose fragments, holograph and typescript carbon typescript, corrected, undated (Box 11)
    - "Robert Burns," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 11)
    - The Saturday Review (anthology edited by Edward Davison), draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 11)
    - "The Snare," lyrics by Edward Davison, music by Louise E. Hofer, draft, holograph, undated (Box 11)
    - Some Modern Poets: list of persons to whom book was sent for criticism, typescript, undated (Box 11)
    - "The Stuff of Civilization," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 11)
    - University of Colorado honors convocation address. Honorary doctorate for Robert Frost, typescript (copies), undated (Box 11)
    - "The University [of Colorado's] cultural function and the war", circa 1942-1943 (Box 11)
  - Writings of George Norlin
    - Address on architectural development on the campus at Boulder, typescript carbon, 1940 June 9 (Box 12)
    - "Artists We Will Be, Antibarbarians," draft, typescript (copy)., 1938 June 12 (Box 12)
      University of Colorado baccalaureate address
    - "Valiant for Truth," draft, typescript (copy), 1940 June 10 (Box 12)
      University of Wyoming commencement speech
    - "A Way of Life," draft, typescript, 1934 June 10 (Box 12)
      Baccalaureate address of University of Colorado
    - "Beauty," draft, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - "Introduction," draft, autograph manuscript, 1940 September 18 (Box 12)
    - "Thoughts of One in Solitary Confinement," draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 12)
    - "Pedestriana" (poems), drafts, typescript, undated (Box 12)
  - Writings of Others
    Arranged alphabetically by author. Unidentified authors are filed at the end.
    - Allen, Hervey. "Question" (poem), draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 12)
    - Armstrong, Martin. "Gold" (poem), draft, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 12)
    - Campbell, A. I. "The Captain's Harbinger" (poem), draft, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 12)
    - Eagleson, Harvey and Howard Mumford Jones. "King Gunnar Takes a Wife," draft, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - Harwood, H. C. Untitled poem, draft, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 12)
    - Haworth, Frank. "She Walks in Beauty," lyrics by Lord Byron, music by Frank Haworth, draft, autograph manuscript (copy), 1953 April (Box 12)
    - Haworth, Frank. "Evening," lyrics by V. Sackville West, music by Frank Haworth, draft, autograph manuscript (copy) (Box 12)
    - Jones, Howard Mumford. Four poems, drafts, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - Kendon, Frank. Five poems, drafts, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 12)
    - Knight, Eric. "The Author, Peace and War," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, 1941 July (Box 12)
      Lecture presented at the Writers' Conference
    - Miller, Frank. "Prothalamion" (poem), draft, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - O., P. T. Poems, drafts, autograph manuscript, 1921, undated (Box 12)
    - Rickwood, Edgell. "The Tired Lover" (poem), draft, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 12)
    - Trench, Herbert. "Song of the Larks at Dawn" (poem), draft, typescript carbon, 1922 (Box 12)
    - Twitchett, E. G. "Sonnet to the Heart" (poem), draft, autograph manuscript, undated (Box 12)
    - Warren, Robert Penn. Two poems: "Athenian Death" and "Love's Parable," fair copies, typescript, undated (Box 12)
    - Unidentified author. University of Colorado commencement address, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 12)
    - Unidentified author. Untitled two act play, draft, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 12)
    - Unidentified authors. Untitled song lyrics, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 12)
    - Unidentified authors. Poems, drafts, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1914, undated (Box 12)
- Administrative Files, 1940-1949; Series IV; 0.21; (1 box)
  Organized into three subseries: University of Colorado, Washington and Jefferson University, and The Writers' Conference.
  - University of Colorado
    - Records concerning the death of George Norlin, 1942 (Box 13)
    - Poll of student and faculty opinion, 1941 March 24 (Box 13)
  - Washington and Jefferson University
    - Memoranda and addresses, 1946-1949 (Box 13)
  - The Writers' Conference
    - Press releases, 1940-1942, undated (Box 13)
    - Publicity file, 1942-1946 (Box 13)
- Photographs, 1918-1962; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  Photographs include portraits and snapshots, with subjects ranging from poets and authors to personnel and prisoners of the Fort Kearney Prisoner of War Camp. Images of Edward Davison include formal portraits and family snapshots. Most subjects are identified on the verso of photographic prints.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject. Group photographs and unidentified photographs are filed at the end.
  - "A" - "K" General, circa 1920-1950; 19 photographs (Box 14)
  - Baker, George, Sgt. "The Sad Sack: Dream," photograph of a cartoon strip, undated (Box 14)
  - Davison, Edward, circa 1920-1962; 17 photographs (Box 14)
  - Davison, Natalie Weiner, undated
  - Davison, Peter, 1929-1951; 7 photographs (Box 14)
  - Evans, Anne, undated
  - Experimental Administrative School for Selected German Prisoners of War, Fort Kearney, Rhode Island, 1945 November (Box 14)
  - France & U.S.A., 1945, undated; 9 photographs (Box 14)
  - "L" - "Z" General, circa 1920-1950; 23 photographs (Box 14)
  - Military photographs, circa 1945; 23 photographs (Box 14)
  - Norlin, George, 1939 (Box 14)
  - Priestly, J. B., 1950 December; 2
    Includes an image of J. B. Priestly's home, signed by J. B. Priestly.
  - Sunflower Project, undated; 3 photographs (Box 14)
  - Group photographs, 1918-1960, undated; 29 photographs (Box 14)
  - Unidentified, 1920, undated; 3; 11 photographs (Box 14)
- Personal Papers, 1920-1951; Series VI; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Financial papers, 1920-1949 (Box 15)
  - Harper and Brothers contracts, 1925-1939 (Box 15)
  - Harper and Brothers royalty statements, 1931-1951 (Box 15)
  - Biographical information, 1942-1947, undated (Box 15)
  - Curriculum Vitae of Edward Davison, undated (Box 15)
  - Recommendation for Award of Distinguished Service Medal, typescript (copies), 1945 November 28 (Box 15)
  - Nine Poems: certificate of copyright registration, Library of Congress copyright office, 1938 March 2 (Box 15)
  - Certificates, 1896-1952
  - Legion of Merit citation, circa 1945 (Box 15)
  - Diplomas, 1921-1934; 2
- Artwork, 1940-1959; Series VII; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically by artist.
  - H., R. Untitled pen and ink drawing, undated
  - Horgan, Paul. Cartoons., 1956-1959 (Box 16)
  - Horgan, Paul. "Animal Society", 1956-1959 (Box 16)
  - Horgan, Paul. "Sante Fe Season" (cartoons), 1956-1959 (Box 16)
    Accompanied by a note to Natalie Davison
  - Lindsay, Vachel. "Butterflies", undated
  - Mackenzie, T. "Crock of Gold" (wood engraving), undated (Box 16)
  - Mackenzie, T. "The Enigma" (pen and ink drawing), undated (Box 16)
  - Mackenzie, T. "Orpheus" (wood engraving), trial proof, undated (Box 16)
  - Mackenzie, T. "The Street" (wood engraving), undated (Box 16)
  - Robinson, Boardman. Untitled crayon drawing, circa 1940
  - Unidentified artist. "The Garden" (wood engraving), undated (Box 16)
- Printed Material, 1919-1959; IIX.; 2.04; (3 boxes)
  Organized into two subseries: Military Publications, and Clippings.
  Printed material includes a substantial quantity of Army publications from the Second World War, including pamphlets and guides printed for army personnel, and publications of the Prisoner of War Special Projects Division.
  - Military Publications
    - War Department Pamphlets, undated
      Arranged alphabetically.
      - Facts vs. Fantasy, 1944 November (Box 17)
      - German Phrase Book, 1943 November 30 (Box 17)
      - Information for Soldiers Going Back to Civilian Life, 1944 March 4 (Box 17)
      - Japanese Language Guide, 1943 (Box 17)
      - MP: The Story of the Corps of Military Police, undated (Box 17)
      - Our Red Army Ally, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to Australia, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to Burma, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to Egypt, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to France, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to Hawaii, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to India, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to Iran, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to Netherlands East Indies, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to New Caledonia, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to New Guinea, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to New Zealand, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to North Africa, undated (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to Panama, 1943 (Box 17)
      - Pocket Guide to West Africa, undated (Box 17)
      - The Races of Mankind, 1943 (Box 17)
      - The Re-education of German Prisoners of War, 1945 December (Box 17)
      - A Short Guide to Syria, undated (Box 17)
      - The Special Service Division, undated (Box 17)
      - What About the German Prisoner?, 1944 November (Box 17)
      - You Don't Think..., undated (Box 17)
    - Other Army publications
      - Armed Forces Talk, Issues 223-270, 1948 (Box 17)
      - Army Orientation Course: Training Guide and Material, 1943 August 14 (Box 17)
      - Army Talk, Issues 31-60 and supplement, 1944-1945 (Box 17)
      - The Coast Artillery Corps of the United States Army, 1943 (Box 17)
      - The Corps of Engineers of the United States Army, 1943 (Box 17)
      - Deutsche Konzentrations- und Gefangenenlager: Was die amerikanischen und britischen Armeen vorfanden, 1945 April (Box 17)
      - Das Dritte Reich, undated (Box 17)
      - "Good Staff Work", 1945 May (Box 17)
      - "How the Army teaches democracy to German prisoners of war" (poster), undated
      - History of Sunflower Project, undated (Box 17)
      - I&E Digest, volume 3, no. 2, 1946 March (Box 17)
      - "Induction Data: Results of Examination of Selectees at Induction Stations", 1943 December 4 (Box 17)
      - "Office of the Provost Marshal General: Poll of German Prisoner of War Opinion", undated (Box 17)
      - Officers' Call: Problems of the Army, undated (Box 17)
      - Orientation Fact Sheets, undated (Box 17)
      - "Report to the Army", 1949 April 1 (Box 17)
      - What the Soldier Thinks, Volume 1, no. 1-4, 1943-1944 (Box 17)
  - Clippings
    - Personal, 1933-1959; 3 (Box 17)
    - Military, circa 1942-1946; 5 (Box 18)
    - General, 1922-1947, undated; 4 (Box 18)
- Subject Files, 1919-1960; Series IX; 0.42; (1 box)
  Subject files include notes, clippings, correspondence, and writings.
  - Allen, Hervey, 1948, undated (Box 20)
  - Coulton, G. G., 1919-1921 (Box 20)
  - Davison, Edward, 1927-1959; 3 (Box 20)
  - Frost, Robert, 1949, 1960 (Box 20)
  - Horgan, Paul, undated (Box 20)
  - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1938, undated (Box 20)
  - Knight, Eric, undated (Box 20)
  - Lader, Lawrence, 1946 August (Box 20)
  - Marshall, S. L. A., 1948 April 16 (Box 20)
  - Mencken, H. L., undated (Box 20)
  - Moore, Doris Langley, undated (Box 20)
  - Norlin, George, 1932-1939 (Box 20)